<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
	<properties>
		<title>Overview</title>
	</properties>
	<body>
		<section name="eDelivery - Overview">
			<p>
				The SPOCS eDelivery concept defines an interoperability layer to
				interconnect secure and trustworthy eDelivery systems
				established in
				the EU Member States. The different solutions are connected via
				Gateways, which are Web Services
				communicating via a common SOAP
				profiling as specified by ETSI TS 102 640 SOAP
				binding profile, part
				of the ETSI
				"Registered E-Mail (REM)" specification.
				<br></br>
				The picture below shows a snapshot of solutions connected mid 2012;
				Romania and Sweden signalled plans to join
				in course of 2012.
			</p>
			<p>
				<div style="text-align: center;">
					<img src="images/InterconnectNetworkSnapshot.png" width="670"
						height="370" alt="SPOCS eDelivery Network Snapshot" />
				</div>
			</p>
			<subsection name="eDelivery Gateway">
				<p>
					SPOCS provides a generic Gateway where national eDelivery solutions
					have
					to be connected to via an adapter to facilitate the mapping of
					domestic message format and packaging to the one used
					on the
					interoperability layer.
					<br />
					The Gatways must account for the mapping of organisational,
					semantical and technical layers in the different eDelivery realms:
					<br />
					<br />
					<div style="text-align: center;">
						<img src="images/GatewayMappingLayers.png" width="720" height="320"
							alt="Mapping Layers" />
					</div>
					<br />
					For the technical and semantical layer, a comfortable Java API is
					provided for converting in- and outbound messages from/to the
					respective domestic format. On the organisational layer, a base
					conformance level is defined and provions are given to establish
					mutual trust.
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Interconnect Protocol">
				<p>

					For the „SPOCS Interconnect“ interoperability layer, the Web
					Services protocol stack has been chosen as the base
					technology set.
					For serving the particular SPOCS requirements appropriate
					protocols
					or protocol extensions have
					been designed, all based on SOAP,
					WS-Addressing, WS-Security and
					underlying mechanisms for message
					security,
					SAML token profiled according STORK for authentication,
					HTTP, SSL/TLS
					and other proven technologies.
					<br />
					A "normalized" message format is defined, enabling the mapping of
					domestic message structuring/packaging formats
					to the SPOCS
					interconnect one and vice versa. First of all, this
					concept
					addresses meta information related to
					the payload. Many automated
					processes rely on meta data for further
					processing and distribution
					outside the core
					transport infrastructure, thus provisions must be
					given for interoperable
					cross-solution mapping of such
					information.
					<br />
					In course of the SPOCS project, the protocol was standardised by
					ETSI ESI as TS 102 640 "SOAP binding profile" mentioned above.
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Evidences to control message delivery status">
				<p>
					According the REM specification, SPOCS eDelivery uses REM
					Evidences for control, proof or notification of the
					dispatched
					message flow. In a nutshell, evidences provide for a valid proof
					of
					end-to-end message delivery. Alike the
					message itself, evidences can
					be converted from/to the corresponding
					domestic format for delivery
					status control information.
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="SAML Token used for end entity authenticity attestation">
				<p>
					National solutions use different mechanisms and token for
					attesting
					authenticity of end entities. For this purpose,
					SPOCS
					eDelivery uses SAML-Token as specified by the OASIS "Security
					Assertion Markup Language" specification, used in a
					profiling like
					provided by the STORK LSP. Again, alike for the message
					itself,
					SAML token can be converted from/to the
					corresponding domestic
					format/mechanisms for authenticity attestation.
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="SPOCS Trust List to establish cross-solution trust">
				<p>
					National Gateways are seen as part of the national trust domains. A
					single Gateway in a trustworthy manner
					somewhat is acting "on behalf" of the eDelivery domains/realms using this
					specific instance to interconnect to foreign
					solutions; to establish trust between the solutions interconnected via
					Gateways, trust must be established between these
					different Gateways. eDelivery Gateways must be registered in a SPOCS Trust
					List according to ETSI TS 102 231, among other attributes
					exposing X509v3 certificates used by the Gateways for SSL handshake and
					message signing. This transport signature is checked
					by a receiving Gateway to control if the sending Gateway is a
					trusted
					one inside the SPOCS Interconnect trust circle.
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection
				name="The eDelivery open modules provide following functionalities:">
				<ul>
					<li>API to convert messages between domestic format and the one
						used on the interoperability layer ("REMDispatch") </li>
					<li>Validation of correct format of messages / message parts</li>
					<li>Application and Validation of signatures applied to messages /
						message parts</li>
					<li>Generation of Evidences, access to such objects and contained
						elements and attributes</li>
					<li>Generation of SAML token attesting end entity authenticity,
						access to such objects and contained elements and attributes</li>
					<li>Transparent target Gateway discovery on base of recipients's
						eDelivery domain</li>
					<li>Trust establishment/validation between Gateways: transparent
						handshake with SPOCS TL</li>
				</ul>

			</subsection>
			<p>
				The present documentation consist of following sections:
				<ul>
					<li>
						<a href="specification.html">Architecture, Specification Intro</a>
						- gives an overview about the eDelivery architecture and specification
					</li>
					<li>
						<a href="software_prerequisites.html">Software and Periquisites</a>
						- How to gather and install the software; runtime perequsites
					</li>
					<li>
						<a href="setup.html">Setting up a national adapter</a>
						- Template and cookbook to get started with a national adapter
					</li>
					<li>
						<a href="tslregistration.html">Registration in SPOCS Trust List</a>
						- Detail to register and maintain a Gateway entry in the SPOCS TL
					</li>
					<li>
						<a href="testing.html">Support for Testing</a>
						- gives an overview of tools provided for testing
					</li>
					<li>
						<a href="license.html">License</a>
						- Information about the eDelivery open modules license
					</li>
					<li>
						<a href="faq.html">FAQ</a>
						- eDelivery FAQs
					</li>
					<li>
						<a href="roadmap.html">Roadmap</a>
						- gives an overview about future developments
					</li>
					<li>
						<a href="contact.html">Contact</a>
						- contact details
					</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
		</section>

		<section name="Support">
		</section>
	</body>
</document>