<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
	<properties>
		<title>Specification</title>
	</properties>
	<body>
		<section name="Specification">
			<subsection name="Architecture Overview">
				<p>
					Following sections give a brief overview about the eDelivery
					specification and open module structure.
					As mentioned in section
					<a href="index.html">
						<u>Overview</u>
					</a>
					, messages in the domestic format and packaging
					of the national solutions are mapped by
					<b>Gateways</b>
					to/from a common exchange format.
					<br />
					<br />
					Following picture gives an overview of the flow of message delivery
					from a sender in Memberstate A
					to a recipient in Memberstate B, both using their domestic eDelivery
					management domains (MD) allocated in their
					national trust realms, which are connected via Gateways for cross-MD
					communication. The bold green
					arrows represent the normal dispatch message flow, while dotted arrows
					represent delivery of evidences
					generated on the dispatch message route for attestation of delivery status.
					<a name="FlowOverview" id="FlowOverview"></a>
					<div align="center">
						<img src="images/FlowOverview.png" width="675" height="450"
							style="border:2px solid black" alt="General flow overview" />
					</div>
					<br />
					Gateways exchange SOAP messages using this common format in the
					SOAP body. The generic part of the
					Gateway implementation is provided as open module, offering an API to be
					used by adapters to be set up
					for each specific national solution connecting to the SPOCS eDelivery
					Network.
					<br />
					For outbound messages, the generic Gateway API provides a
					convenient interface to build up the the
					the interoperability layer message as well as message part containers
					<ul>
						<li>
							<a href="#REMDispatch">
								<u>REM Dispatch</u>
							</a>
						</li>
						<li>
							<a href="#REMEvidence">
								<u>REM Evidence</u>
							</a>
						</li>
						<li>
							<a href="#SAMLToken">
								<u>SAML Token.</u>
							</a>
						</li>
					</ul>
					On the inbound side, these containers are offered Java objects to
					the national adapter, in this case
					with a convenience interface to access object parts and details.
					<br />
					<br />
					Transparent for the national adapters, the generic Gateway part
					performs
					<ul>
						<li>message format/schema validation</li>
						<li>message and message parts signature application/validation
						</li>
						<li>address resolution, determination of target Gateway</li>
						<li>generation respective processing of SOAP envelope including
							WS-Security entries</li>
						<li>reliable submission/reception of message on base of
							SOAP/http-binding, WS Addressing and WS ReliableMessaging</li>
						<li>exception issuance in case of errors / appearance of evidences
							in case of delivery process problems</li>
						<li>
							handshake with SPOCS Trust List, Gateway/Gateway authentication:
							<a href="#SPOCSTL">
								<u>cross-solution trust establishment</u>
							</a>
							.
						</li>
					</ul>

				</p>
			</subsection>
			<a name="REMDispatch" id="REMDispatch"></a>
			<subsection name="Interoperability layer message structure">
				<p>
					Transport between Gateways is based on SOAP, using standard Web
					Servcies bricks WS-Addressing for addressing and
					WS-Security for message security. WS-ReliableMessaging is used in addtion to
					ensure transport reliability.
					According functionality is given by standard WS-Stack implementations, OSS
					ones are widely available
					(like
					<a href="http://metro.java.net">
						<u>Metro</u>
					</a>
					as used by the SPOCS implementation).
					<br />
					Below a glance of the constituents of the standard SOAP header
					blocks, WS-ReliableMessaging headers omitted for brevity:
					<br />
					<div align="left">
						<img src="images/SOAPHeader.png" width="350" height="400"
							style="border:2px solid black" alt="SOAP Header structure" />
					</div>
					<br />
					Next picture gives a schema overview of the message, as carried in
					the SOAP body.
					<br />
					The detailed schema is specified in
					<a
						href="SpecDocuments/SPOCS_D3.2_Appendix3_eDelivery_Interconnect_Protocol_V2.0.pdf"
						type="application/pdf">
						<u>SPOCS Interconnect Protocol specification</u>
					</a>
					, which is based on
					<a href="SpecDocuments/ts_1026400603v010101p.pdf" type="application/pdf">
						<u>ETSI TS 102 640 ("REM")SOAP Binding Profile</u>
						.
					</a>


					<div align="left">
						<img src="images/REMDispatchHighlevelRedef.png" width="500"
							height="600" />
					</div>
					<br />
					A dispatch according the REM specification (schema prefix
					"remsoap:") contains the mandatory containers
					<dl class="cssmenu">
						<dt>OriginalMsg</dt>
						<dd>the unchanged original message</dd>
						<dt>MsgMetaData</dt>
						<dd>message meta data derived from according original message
							items, carrying </dd>
						<ul>
							<ul>
								<li>DeliveryContraints: time stamps like initial send, obsolete
									after etc. </li>
								<li>Originators: eAddress and optional details for initiator,
									sender if different, reply-to</li>
								<li>Destinations: eAddress and optional details for recipients
									(in role "To" and "cc") </li>
								<li>MsgIdentification: Message-Id as assigned by source MD,
									optional referenced ones ("in reply to", other references)) </li>
							</ul>
						</ul>
						<dt>ds:Signature</dt>
						<dd>
							signature covering the whole REMDispatch, applied by the Gateway
							performing
							the conversion from domestic to interoperability (REM/SOAP) format.
							<b>Mandatory element</b>
							in abberration to the REM specification.
						</dd>
					</dl>
					Additional optional containers:
					<dl class="cssmenu">
						<dt>NormalizedMsg</dt>
						<dd>
							Besides the
							<i>MsgMetaData</i>
							mentioned above, the content of the original message should
							be converted to this "normalized" xml structure, thus enabling the
							receiving Gateway to convert to the
							according items of the domestic message format in use on that side. This
							container covers elements and sub-containers
							for message-subject, -comments and keywords for payload
							classification like e.g. related business-scenario or
							-process-id,
							message body text, -attachments, and a
							<i>xs:any</i>
							element, mainly foreseen to borrow structured xml payload in
							user/scenario defined namespaces,
							usable for machine processable payload.
						</dd>
						<dt>REMMDEvidencelist</dt>
						<dd>
							In general, a source Gateway generates an Evidence of
							(un)successful submission
							of a dispatch. In the successful case, this Evidence is appended to
							the Dispatch in this element
							<i>REMMDEvidenceList</i>
							and delivered to
							the target Gateway. It's on behalf of the national adapter on the
							receiving side, how to deal with this Evidence, e.g. delivery to
							the recipient, may be after conversion to a domestic Evidence
							format in use. At least, this Evidence should be serialized and
							saved for later access,
							as subsequent (asynchronous) Evidences related to this Dispatch can
							easily be build up using this
							initial Evidence already carrying most of the details needed.
							<br />
							See
							<a href="#REMEvidence">
								<u>REM Evidence Overview</u>
							</a>
							for more detailed explanations.
						</dd>

					</dl>
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<a name="REMEvidence" id="REMEvidence"></a>
			<subsection name="REM Evidence overview">
				<p>
					An Evidence is a message carrying information on evidences raised
					on the message route. Different
					evidences may be raised by all entities involved in the message transport
					and may be targeted to
					different consumers (transport nodes and/or Senders as well as Recipients).
					They serve as control,
					proof or notification of the Dispatch message flow. Evidence data is
					digitally signed and thus
					transferable, i.e. it can be used by each party to prove authenticity of the
					Evidence without the
					need to involve the issuing entity. An Evidence message MAY be amended
					by the Dispatch message the
					Evidence is related to. According to the specification ETSI TS 102 640
					adopted, the technical term
					for this type of message is
					<i>REMMDMessage</i>
					, which contains one or more
					<i>REMEvidence</i>
					containers in a sequence
					<i>REMMDEvidenceList</i>
					.
					<br />
					<br />
					High level overview about information carried in a REMEvidence:
					<br />
					<div align="center">
						<img src="images/REMEvidenceDetails.png" width="380" height="400" />
					</div>
					<br />
					A RemEvidence XML container should be signed digitally. Detailed
					specification is given in section 5 of
					<a href="SpecDocuments/ts_10264002v020201p.pdf" type="application/pdf">
						<u>ETSI TS 102 640 ("REM") Part 2: Data requirements, Formats and
							Signatures for REM</u>
						.
					</a>
					For profiling of this specification according to the SPOCS
					requirements see section 2 of
					<a
						href="SpecDocuments/SPOCS_D3.2_Appendix3_eDelivery_Interconnect_Protocol_V2.0.pdf"
						type="application/pdf">
						<u>SPOCS Interconnect Protocol specification</u>
					</a>
					.
					<br />
					<br />
					The
					<a href="#FlowOverview">
						<u>graphical overview of the message flow</u>
					</a>
					on top of this page shows a logical view, which evidences are
					produced by which node on
					the message route in the different situations during dispatch
					delivery:
					<br />

					<table>
						<tr>
							<th>Node</th>
							<th>Description</th>
							<th>(logical) Evidence Type</th>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>MD Sender</td>
							<td>May produce an Evidence of rejection or acceptance and
								submission</td>
							<td>
								Feature of domestic solution, out of scope for SPOCS eDelivery.
								<br />
								Information like initial submission time and other details
								<br />
								should be given to GW MS A by national adapter, to be included
								in the Evidence produced there subsequently.
							</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>GW MS A</td>
							<td>Evidence of rejection or acceptance and submission to GW MS B
							</td>
							<td>
								<b>SubmissionAcceptanceRejection</b>
							</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>GW MS B</td>
							<td>Evidence of rejection or acceptance and relay to recipients
								MD</td>
							<td>
								<b>RelayAcceptanceRejection</b>
								<br />
								<i>
									Only to be provided, if (non)delivery - see next row -
									<br />
									can only be provided in an asynchronous manner
								</i>
							</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>MD Recipient</td>
							<td>Evidence of non-delivery or successful delivery to recipients
								message box</td>
							<td>
								Initially generated in domestic format, to be routed to
								<br />
								national adpater of GW MS B to produce a
								<br />
								<b>DeliveryNonDeliveryToRecipient</b>
								,
								<br />
								to be send back to GW MS A for delivery to the initial sender
							</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>MD Recipient</td>
							<td>
								Evidence of non-retrieval or retrieval by recipient
								<br />
								- only if domestic solution provides this functionality!
								<br />
								The
								<i>non</i>
								case may e.g. express
								<i>not in time</i>
								, depending on local policy
							</td>
							<td>
								Initially generated in domestic format, to be routed to
								<br />
								national adapter of GW MS B to produce a
								<br />
								<b>RetrievalNonRetrievalByRecipient</b>
								,
								<br />
								to be send back to GW MS A for delivery to the initial sender
							</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>MD Recipient</td>
							<td>
								Evidence of acceptance or non-acceptance by recipient
								<br />
								- only if domestic solution provides this functionality!
							</td>
							<td>
								Initially generated in domestic format, to be routed to
								<br />
								national adapter of GW MS B to produce a
								<br />
								<b>AcceptanceRejectionByRecipient</b>
								,
								<br />
								to be send back to GW MS A for delivery to the initial sender
							</td>
						</tr>
					</table>
					<i>
						Legend:
						<br />
						- MD: Management Domain
						<br />
						- GW: Gateway
						<br />
						- MS A/B: Memberstate A/B
					</i>
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<a name="SAMLToken" id="SAMLToken"></a>
			<subsection name="Usage of SAML Token for end entity authentication">
				<p>
					As of today, domestic eID / eDelivery solutions use different
					mechanisms and/or token to attest authenticity of communication
					participants.
					In course of the last decade, token as specified by the
					<a
						href="http://docs.oasis-open.org/security/saml/v2.0/saml-core-2.0-os.pdf">
						<u>OASIS Security Assertion Markup Language (SAML) Specification
						</u>
					</a>
					have more and more be broadly recognized and accepted as a
					standardised format and trusted way to
					exchange such information. The
					<a href="http://www.eid-stork.eu">
						<u>EU LSP STORK </u>
					</a>
					on eID interoperability adopted this work, detailed in an own
					profiling of SAML Token as specified
					in section 6.3. of
					<u>STORK D5.1.8.b - Interface Specification</u>
					.
					In expectation of future usage of STORK results in the whole EU,
					SPOCS just inherited this
					STORK SAML Token profiling.
					<br />
					But due to actual lack of SAML Token issuance, usage and mutual
					recognition in the MS, these Token
					have to be generated and validated by the Gateways (or services related
					to Gateways).
					Based on details to be provided by the national adapters - mainly
					information on the subject to be
					authenticated and the subjects authentication strongness in effect in the
					respective national
					infrastructure. The authentication level must be mapped to one of the four
					predefined STORK
					<b>Quality Authentication Assurance</b>
					level
					<b>(QAA)</b>
					.The generic part of the Gateway provides
					functionality to generate and sign a SAML Token of type "Sender Vouches"
					(explanation see SAML specification). On the receiving side, this
					Token
					is validated by means of his signature; it's a matter of the national
					adapter to transform the
					details contained in the Token to the domestic authentication attestation
					means/-token.
					<br />
					<br />
					Details and an example for these SAML Sender Vouches Token is given
					in
					<a
						href="SpecDocuments/SPOCS_D3.2_Appendix3_eDelivery_Interconnect_Protocol_V2.0.pdf"
						type="application/pdf">
						<u>section 4 of the SPOCS Interconnect Protocol specification</u>
					</a>
					.
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<a name="SPOCSTL" id="SPOCSTL"></a>
			<subsection name="Establishing cross-domain Trust: SPOCS Trust List">
				<p>
				</p>
			</subsection>
		</section>
	</body>
</document>